And just to convince you, I'm actually
qualified to talk to you about this. I
should introduce myself. Uh my name is
Ed Donner. I'm the co-founder and CTO of
an AI startup called nebula.io. You
should go check him out. I spent most of
my career working for JP Morgan. I
started out in London, which is where
I'm from originally. I moved to Tokyo
for a few months and then ended up in
NYC, which is where I am right now. And
at the end of my time at JP Morgan, I
was a managing director leading a team
of about 300 technologists working in
software engineering and Python and in
uh analytics. And before my current role
at Nebula, I founded an AI startup
called Untapped. And Untapped was
acquired in 2021. And this picture here
is my magical moment, which which is a
billboard in Time Square announcing the
acquisition of my startup. And in case
you you you don't believe me, you're
like, that could be any picture from
Times Square, I will tell you that if
you if you squint and look very
carefully, the thing I just circled in
green there is me. Uh so there is
evidence of this. I am I am there uh on
that billboard. And the other reason I
show this, not just to show off about my
moment in Time Square, but also because
I actually live like one block from Time
Square. It's it's very rare for people
to live in in this because it's such a
sort of touristy uh area to be in, but
that is where I live about a block that
way behind that guitar. If that guitar
weren't there, you would you would see
my window that I'm looking out onto
right now. Uh so that that is where I
am. If you can picture me right there
making this and look, it's customary in
these things to to show like a like a
like a hobby, like something I do
outside work. And so I have this picture
of me just having flown that airplane to
to be like, look, I can do things other
than being a nerd. But in fact, I am a
big old nerd. Most of what I do in my
spare time is more working with LLMs.
And I'm honestly really bad at anything
else. So So you're lucky. You're lucky
that that this is this is how we get to
work together because this is all I'm
good at. And as it turns out, when I
flew that plane, I was really bad at it.
And so if you get get on a plane and you
see that it's that it's me there behind
the stick, you want to be looking for a
parachute really quickly. You ought to
be getting out of there. But if you find
yourself on a course and I'm there and
I'm teaching about LLMs, then
congratulations. You've come to the
right place. That's what I'm good at.
And that brings me to the other thing I
do, which is explaining LLM and agents
to other people. I speak at conferences
and live events. And of course, I teach
a bunch of courses on Udemy. Uh, it's
been my great joy. But I have more than
400,000 people on my various different
courses, and I absolutely love it. And
I'm very good at interacting with
people. If you send me a message, I will
reply. And it's not an agent. It's
really me. Uh, try me and I'll reply
right away. I very much enjoy
interacting with people and I I love the
whole process of explaining things and I
can't wait to be doing that with you
over the next three weeks. So, as I say,
I have five other courses on Udemy. And
you might be wondering, how exactly does
this fit in with the other things I do?
I've got a course that's called AI
Builder that is about building uh
solutions using platforms like NAN and
11 Labs, agents, and voice agents. I've
got three different courses for AI
engineers. There's a core track, an
agentic track, and an MLOps track. And
then I have a leadership course, a
briefing for business leaders and for
tech people too on what it takes to
build a durable AI business and deliver
AI to production and building a road map
to deliver commercial impact. And so
this is my latest course. This is AI
coder. This is for people who want to
write code using AI and agents to help
them. Now all of these courses I often
get the question of which order should I
take your courses and I always say look
I've built these courses to be
complimentary. If there is overlap then
it's only additive. It makes absolute
sense to take them in whatever order
works best for you. If if you're looking
for an order to take them in then I do
have a web page on my homepage called
curriculum which lays out the
curriculum, explains how they're related
to each other and perhaps the most
natural order to take them in. And it's
always possible that I've made more
courses since since I'm since I'm
speaking to you now, in which case
you'll find those other courses also
explained on my curriculum page and laid
out so that you can connect the dots
between them. But this course that
you're on right now is a bit of an odd
one out. And let me tell you what I mean
by that. Most of the courses that I
teach, if not all the courses I teach
are about how do you use technology? How
do you write code in order to make AI
platforms, AI products or AI agents? So,
it's about using code to make agents.
This course is kind of the other way
round. This is about using agents to
write code and that code can also itself
be about new AI products. So, it's
certainly worth having this in mind that
that most of my courses are about people
who want to build AI. How do you write
code to build AI? And this is about how
do you use AI in order to write code and
and there's something circular going on
there which is confusing but hopefully
that's clear to you and you understand
what I mean. That's why this course is a
bit different to all of the others
although it's still very complimentary
to everything else. And now I've had a
particular strategy when putting
together this course curriculum for AI
coder and that is that I've tried to
combine both breadth and depth. I've
tried to think about covering this this
whole space quite broadly, but also
going deep on what I think is most
interesting and important. So, in terms
of breadth, I wanted to make sure that
we touch on a large number of different
kinds of tools that you may encounter in
different jobs and different
environments or working with others.
Now, one of these might be your
favorite. It might become your go-to,
but I certainly want to make sure that
you've had exposure to lots of them. It
doesn't mean that you need to pay for
them, that you could just watch me or
there's there's free trials of most of
these, but certainly I'd like you to
have that exposure so you feel
comfortable knowing about all these
different tools out there, at least the
most popular ones. But I do want to go
deep on one front. I want to go deep on
CLI coding in clawed code or also
potentially in open code or or others
that are similar. So that is how we will
go deep. And in weeks two and three,
we're going to go much deeper on that
front. So I want to leave you with both
the breadth and the depth, combine them
both for this course. And that's a nice
segue to laying out the three-w weekek
program that I have in store for you.
And this this is the curriculum
construct that we will come back to lots
of times. I'm going to show you that
there's going to be three types of
session. There's going to be ones where
we focus on core skills. There's going
to be ones when we talk about actual
platforms, products, things like codeex
and claude code and cursor. And then
there's going to be real commercial
projects. Aside from today, which
doesn't count, they're going to be real
commercial projects all the way through.
So these are the three different types
of session that we will have. And with
that, I have divided your learning into
three weeks. Week one, I'm calling it
vibe coding for fun and profit. Week one
is going to be about vibe coding. Week
two is using a new term that's kind of
coming up that was sort of coined by by
an amazing writer, Simon Wilson, vibe
engineering, which is more about being a
pro, going beyond vibe coding into using
this tooling for more professional
purposes. And then week three is a
gentic engineering as an expert. This is
where you are. You are really at the
sort of top of what is possible, what is
capable using the best of this
technology. And on each of these weeks,
I have got five days worth of material.
Everything is divided into five days. Uh
within each of the three weeks, you get
two days off. Uh and you can see how
I've laid it out here for the first
week. We are today in day one, which is
that box on the bottom left, the agentic
coding landscape. That's where we are
right now. And then during the course of
this week, we'll have another purple day
on core skills about the foundations,
agents, context. This is all tomorrow.
Then we're going to have a yellow day
when we look at the different tooling,
cursor, copilot, codeex, anti-gravity.
And then we're going to have two
projects. The first project I'm calling
YOLO, and the second project is a
commercial MVP. We'll be doing all of
that this week, week one, vibe coding
for fun and profit. And then next week,
Vibe Engineering, we go deep into CLI
coding. We're going to be using claude
code and open code and some others.
We're going to look at commands and
checkpoints. This thing called Ralph
loops, which is what I just demoed you
the result of. Uh we're going to be then
looking at MCP skills, plugins, which is
which is going to be really interesting
material and definitely the stuff that
people are debating feverishly at the
moment. We're going to look at building
workflows, working with a team,
debugging when you're when you're trying
to debug uh existing problems or
debugging problems that your AI agent
has built. And then we'll have a really
meaty project at the end of the week, a
SAS platform that we will build
together. We'll be us together and also
with our AI agents and everything will
culminate in week three, which is really
when when we raise the bar. We start
with multi- aents running with lots of
agents and sub aents and using hooks.
We'll spend a whole day digging into
sandboxing perhaps with some other
advanced things thrown in there too.
Such an important topic. Then we will
work on large code bases. This is
certainly where you start to see rough
edges with aentic AI and we'll figure
out what is the survival guide for
working with a large codebase. Then the
really fun topics of of agent swarms and
orchestrators are all the rage. And we
will finally end with a super juicy
capstone project, a fitting finale for
this 3-week curriculum. And at the end
of it, you'll be able to say, "Yes, I am
now an expert, a gentic engineer."
You'll be able to respond to Andre's
tweet and say, "I've got the missing
manual." And you'll be able to build
largecale highquality software with a
team of agents working for